# Samuel Bencivengo

Brooklyn, NY 11218 | 310 • 804 • 2399 | sambencivengo@gmail.com sambencivengo.com | GitHub | Medium | LinkedIn

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Full Stack Developer building projects with JavaScript, Node is, ReactJS and Ruby on Rails. With a decade of working in shipping, sales and the service industry, I have developed strong communication and interpersonal skills. I look forward to taking on new technical challenges and solving problems both cooperatively and independently.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript, ReactJS, Node.js, Git, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Aviary - ReactJS | Rails GitHub | Live Build | Demo

Scraped and created a database of approximately 1200 bird species currently in the United States.

- Built a dynamic and easy to use application allowing users to spot birds, mark their geolocation and save them to a
- Leveraged Rails to generate user cookies, enabling login persistence on page refresh.
- Implemented authorization and authentication on both the frontend and backend of the application.

# Bike About - ReactJS | React Native | Node.js

## Github | Github Mobile

- Built an application for users to record a bike ride with their mobile device and submit it to a database.
- Implemented Leaflet's map API in the desktop client allowing the user's recorded rides to be viewed on a map.
- Programmed the backend using Express for its robust features, MongoDB for the database and Mongoose for object modeling.
- Used bcrypt and JSON web tokens for authentication and authorization.

### EventsNow - ReactJS | Rails

## GitHub Backend | GitHub Frontend

- Built and helped design a scheduling and hosting application, allowing users to create and RSVP to events.
- Modeled a custom database using REST API, Active Record and Ruby on Rails.
- Implemented authentication and authorization to prevent unauthorized users from accessing the database.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

D.S. & DURGA Brooklyn, NY 10/2018 - 08/2021

Shipping Coordinator/Salesperson

delivery.

- Worked between a studio warehouse in Brooklyn and a shop in Soho for a boutique, independent perfume company. Palletized, safely packaged and loaded up to \$50K+ shipments and organized transport to JFK for international
- Trained in handling hazmat goods to adequately label a shipment for safe handling and remedy potential accidents.
- Managed and met overseas shipping requirements.
- Developed expertise in perfumery and fragrances in order to educate customers and sell products on the floor.
- Ensured a positive, enjoyable experience for customers to build return sales in highly foot trafficked areas with strong local competition.

Wife/Lil' Sister Brooklyn, NY 06/2017 - 10/2018 Cafe Manager

- Led a 2-person crew in a fast paced cafe.
- Managed inventory management and handled product purchasing.
- Guaranteed that product delivery met customer expectations and was served with attention to detail.
- Worked with upper management to complete forms and handle insurance filing with the city to enable the cafe to re-open quickly.

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Brooklyn, NY 09/2021 - 01/2021

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript

San Francisco, CA 09/2012 - 06/2016

San Francisco Art Institute BFA New Genres (3D Rendering & Modeling, Video)